刑法により禁じられた犯罪行為＞
＜５年以下の懲役 または➡
50万円以下の
罰金に処せられます＞
＜後悔しても 元には戻せない＞
不正視聴!?
i realise the screaming pain
hearing loud in my brain
but i'm going straight ahead with the scar
I should just get over it and I should just stop feeling it
wasurete shimaeba ii yo kanjinaku nacchaeba ii
and so I covered my grazed heart
surimuita kokoro ni futa wo shitan da
I don't care if I'm hurt 'cause I don't feel pain anymore
kizutsuitatte heki da yo mou itami wa nai kara ne
all while you limped on while dragging your feet behind you
sono ashi wo hikizuri nagara mo
I had lost sight of myself
miushinatta jibun jishin ga
which had crumbled loudly to the ground
oto wo taete kuzureteita
but then I realised it was just the sound of the wind...
kizukeba kaze no oto dake ga
I came here to tell you something following my deep scars
tsutae ni kita yo kizuato wo tadotte
before I am completely crushed by this vast world
sekai ni oshitsubusarete shimau mae ni
do you remember that sky of tears
oboeteru kana namida no sora wo
that pain protected you for me
ano itami ga kimi no koto wo mamotte kureta
that pain is always protecting you
sono itami ga itsumo kimi wo mamotterunda
can you hear me so am i
The Tale of Jiraiya the Gallant
(綱手)嫌な雨が続くな。
There's no end to this awful rain...
((自来也 : アハハハッ 冗談だ 冗談！
Joking! I'm just joking!
(お前には感謝してる))
You know, I'm grateful to you.
(シズネ)自来也様なら大丈夫です。
あの方がそうそう…。
I'm sure Jiraiya-sama is fine.
He, of all people, wouldn't...
アイツは帰って来ない。
えっ…。
He's not coming back...
Huh?
私はそっちに賭けた。
That's what I bet him.
私の賭けは 必ずハズれるからな。
And I never win my bets.
そういうことですか。
Oh, I see.
((自来也 : 男はフラれて強くなる。
Rejection makes a man stronger.
(それに 幸せなんてのは
男が求めるもんじゃないのぉ))
And besides...
men aren't the ones
who seek happiness.
フッ かっこつけやがって。
What a poser...
帰って来たら そろそろ
かっこつかなくさせてやるかな。
When he gets back...
I won't let him keep his cool.
ペイン お前はいったい何者なんだ。
Pain... What are you?!
(ペイン)ペイン それはオレたち
６人全員を指し示す呼び名だ。
Pain...
That name is an alias that
denotes all six of us.
お お前は その顔…。
Y-You're...!
That face...
弥彦なのか？
Is that you, Yahiko?
((ああ いたな そんなヤツも。
とっくに死んだよ そんなヤツは))
Oh yeah... There was such a guy,
wasn't there?
He died a long time ago.
いったい どういうことだ？
弥彦は死んだんじゃ…。
What's going on?
I thought you said Yahiko died!
それにその目…。
Plus, those eyes...
オレに弥彦の面影を見たか。
You see Yahiko's image in me?
やはりかつての師ではある。
You really are his former Teacher.
だが すでに弥彦は死んだ。
But Yahiko has been dead
for quite some time.
ここにいるのは ペインだ。
All that remains... is Pain.
そんな屁理屈はいい！
なぜお前が輪廻眼を持っている！
Quit it with the wordplay!
Why do you possess the Rinnegan?!
(フカサク)
どういうことじゃ 自来也ちゃん。
What are you talking about,
Jiraiya-chan?
かつての
弟子の１人があのなかにいます。
One of my former students
is among them.
ただその子は
あの目を持ってはいなかった。
Except he didn't use to
possess those eyes...
(シマ)いったい 何が
どうなっとるんじゃ？
What in tarnation is going on?
あのなかに
予言の子が２人もおるんか？
You saying there are
two children of prophecy?
《いや 違う。 輪廻眼を見て➡
No, that's not it either...
When I saw the Rinnegan, I convinced
myself that the first one was Nagato...
最初のヤツを
長門だと思い込んでしまったが➡
わしが知る長門とは違和感がある。
But he's subtly different
from the Nagato I knew of...
それによく見れば
あの６人のなかに➡
Come to think of it,
upon closer inspection,
none of those six remind me of Nagato.
長門の面影を感じるヤツは
１人としていない。
それなのに 弥彦の面影を持ち➡
On the other hand,
one of them resembles Yahiko...
長門の輪廻眼を持つものがいる》
but possesses Nagato's Rinnegan...
弥彦なのか 長門なのか…。
Are you Yahiko... or Nagato?
お前らは いったい何なんだ？
Just what exactly are you?!
我々は ペイン。
We are Pain...
神だ。
We are god.
自来也ちゃん 退け！
Retreat, Jiraiya-chan!
《神だと？》
A god?!
弥彦 なぜお前が
長門の目を持っている？
Yahiko! How could you possess
Nagato's eyes?!
そんなことを知っても
我々には勝てん！
Even if you knew that,
you could not win!
小僧！ あきらめんさい！
Lad! Give up already!
なんとか 隙を見つけて
刺し違えてでも…。
I must find an opening to defeat them,
even if it kills me!
気配が消えた。
I don't sense his presence...
ここは… 結界か…。
This is... a barrier?
《胃液？》
Gastric fluid?
螺旋丸！
Rasengan!
やったのぉ 自来也ちゃん。
You did it, Jiraiya-chan.
(シマ)死んだか…。
Is he dead?
(自来也)結界に引きずり込んで
やっとで 一人か…。
I barely managed to kill one...
only after dragging it into my barrier...
大丈夫か!? 小僧！
くっ… なんとか…。
Are you all right, lad?
Somewhat...
体が… チャクラが乱される！
My body...?!
My chakra's agitated!
これか!?
Is it this?!
正体も奇妙じゃけどの 武器まで
奇妙なものを使うてくるわい。
Their identity is a mystery,
and they seem to use odd weapons too.
コイツらはもう
ただの人じゃあらへんの。
They're no longer mortals...
They're something entirely different.
何か 別のものじゃ。
((誰も 彼の顔を
よく知らないし➡
No one really knows what
he looks like.
実際には
存在しないんじゃないか と➡
And some claim that
he doesn't even exist.
(ウワサする者さえいる))
《自来也 : あの顔…
ヤツは 間違いなく 弥彦だ》
That face...
He is unmistakably Yahiko...
《それなのに
長門の輪廻眼を持っていた。
And yet,
he possesses Nagato's Rinnegan...
弥彦が なんらかの理由で
長門から奪い取ったのか？
Did Yahiko steal them
from Nagato for some reason?
しかし… 他にも
あれだけの輪廻眼がある。
But...
There are other
Rinnegan bearers as well...
いったい どういうことだ…》
So what's going on?
《それに…》
Plus...
((自来也 : だが そういう痛みを
知っているからこそ➡
Understanding such pain enables you
to be kind to others...
人に優しくできることもある。
それが 人だ。
That's what makes us human.
(長門)それって… どういうこと？
What do you mean by that...?
成長するってことだのぉ。
It's called growing up.
(長門)成長するって…
つまり どういうこと？
Growing up? What do you mean?
(自来也)どうするか
自分で考えることだ))
That, you need to figure out yourself.
((ここでは人が死にすぎる。
Too many people die here.
That pain made me grow up.
(それらの痛みが オレを成長させた))
だとすると
やはりコイツが長門か…。
In which case,
does that mean he is Nagato?
んっ!?
そうだ 思い出した！
That's right! Now I remember!
コイツは 長門なんかじゃない！
This one is definitely not Nagato!
どうした!?
この目の前の男➡
What's the matter?
This fellow before us...
前に一度
手合わせしたことがある。
I've fought him before.
大ガマ仙人の予言に従って
旅を始めたばかりの頃 出会った➡
He was a Fuma Clan member
I encountered
right after setting out on my journey,
following the Great Lord Elder's prophecy.
風魔一族の男だ。
この額の傷は わしがつけたもの。
I gave him that scar on his forehead...
なんで そんなヤツが
ここにおるんなら？
So what's a fellow like him
doing here?
ますます ペインのことが
わからんようになったな。
Now I'm even more confused
about this whole Pain mystery.
((大ガマ仙人 : おぬしは
その変革者を導く者じゃ。
You will guide that revolutionary.
いずれ おぬしには大きな選択を
迫られるときが来るじゃろう。
The day will come when you will be
forced to make a critical selection.
わしは
どうすればいいんですか？
What must I do...?
正しく選択するには！
In order to make the right choice?
(夢では 世界を歩いて
本を書いておったのう))
In my dream, you traveled the world,
writing books.
《まさか 予言のとおりなら…》
It can't be...
If this is the prophecy...
わしは もう一度 ヤツらの前に出て
確かめたいことがあります。
I wish to go back and face them
in order to confirm something...
お二人は お帰りください。
You two please go back.
なに!?
ダメじゃ！
What?!
Absolutely not! You will be killed
if you go out again!
次 出ていけば必ず殺される。
さらに眼が増えた。
They have more eyes,
それに結界トラップが二度も通じる
相手じゃありゃせんぞ！
and they will not fall
for the barrier trap twice!
今 ヤツらは
こっちに気づいとらんのじゃけん。
They're not on to us in here yet.
逃げるなら今しかない！
This is our only chance to
make a run for it!
今 出て行けば
殺されるかもしれませんがの。
I may be killed if I go out there...
だが 敵の正体を
つかめるかもしれません。
But I may be able to learn
the truth about them.
この機を逃したら➡
If I let this chance slip by,
もう ここまでペインに近づける者は
たぶん おらんでしょう。
I don't think there's anyone else
who could get as close to Pain.
正体を見抜くチャンスは 今しかない！
This is our only chance to
uncover the truth...
そして… 今こそが
大ガマ仙人の予言された➡
Plus...
This is the time for selection
that the Great Lord Elder prophesied!
選択のとき！
頭と姐さんは
今までのペインの情報と➡
Boss and Ma'am...
please take the intel on Pain
we've gathered so far,
このペインの死体を
持って帰ってくだされ。
as well as this corpse and go back.
そして 綱手に…。
And please tell Tsunade...
それは
かあちゃんだけで十分じゃ。
Ma should be enough for that.
えっ!? しかし！
But...
晩飯までに戻りんさい。
Just return by dinnertime.
ああ 終わったら
自来也ちゃんと一緒に➡
Yup... When we're done here,
I'll bring Jiraiya-chan on over with me.
飯を食いに帰る。
《ありがとう… ございます》
Thank you...
《やっぱり そうだ！》
It's just as I thought!
《コイツら全員
わしの会ったことのある忍だ》
They're all ninjas that
I've encountered before!
《そうか わかったぞ ペインの正体》
That's it!
I've figured out who Pain is!
《ノドが…！》
自来也ちゃん！
My throat...
遅かったな気づくのが。
Jiraiya-chan!
You were too late in figuring it out...
《ペインの正体
頭に伝えなくては…》
I must let Boss know... about
Pain's true identity.
しっかりしろ 自来也ちゃん！
Hang in there, Jiraiya-chan!
《ダメだ… ノドを潰されたか。
It's no good...
My throat has been crushed.
クソッ！ これでは…。
Damn it... At this rate...
ダメだ… 気が遠くなる。
It's useless... I'm passing out...
わしは… 死ぬのか？
Am I... going to die?
失敗なのか？》
Have I failed...?
《自来也 : 忍は生きざまではなく
死にざまの世界…。
It's not how you live,
but how you die in
the ninja world...
忍の人生とはどうやって
生きてきたかではなく➡
A ninja's life is not measured
by how they lived
死ぬまでに何をしたかで
その価値が決まる。
but rather what they managed
to accomplish before their death.
思い返せば
わしの人生は失敗ばかりだった。
Looking back, my life has
been nothing but failures...
綱手にフラれ続け
友を止めることもできず➡
Continually rejected by Tsunade...
Unable to stop my friend...
弟子と師を
守ることもできなかった。
And unable to protect either
my student or my mentor...
火影たちが成した偉業に
比べれば わしのしてきたことは➡
Compared to the great deeds
of the Hokage,
my actions are trifling,
insignificant things indeed.
取るに足らぬ
くだらぬことばかり…。
わしも 歴代火影たちのように
死にたかった。
I wish I could have died like
each of the Hokage.
物語は最後の結びのできで決まる。
A tale is only good as
its final turn of events, the plot twist.
失敗も一興！ その試練が 己を
磨いてくれたと信じ 生きてきた。
Failures must be seen
as mere amusements!
They are trials, which hone your skills.
I lived believing that...
その代わり 今までの失敗を
チャラにするような➡
And in return, I swore I would
accomplish a deed so great
大きな偉業をなし遂げ
立派な忍として死ぬ。
that it would obliterate all
of my failures...
And I'd die a splendid ninja!
そのはずだった。 フフフ…。
At least, that's how it
was supposed to go...
だが その結び…
死にざまがこれか。
But... with my plot twist...
My tale, ending like this...
大ガマ仙人は わしを
変革者を導く者と予言した。
The Great Lord Elder prophesied that
I would guide that revolutionary.
忍の世界の安定と破壊に関わる
大きな選択をする者 と。
A person who will make
a great choice
that will bring either stability
or destruction to the ninja world.
ここで ペインを倒し 暁を止め
忍の世界を救う…。
I thought I would defeat Pain,
stop the Akatsuki,
and save the ninja world
from destruction...
結局 その選択も
失敗してしまった。
But in the end, I failed in
that selection too.
情けないのぉ…。
How pitiful...
これが 自来也豪傑物語の
結びだとはのぉ…。
that this will be the twist to
"The Tale of Jiraiya the Gallant".
くだらぬ物語だった》
What a worthless story...
((ミナト : いいや
そんなことはないです。
No, I don't think so.
This tale is wonderful!
この物語は すばらしいです。
エピソードが 先生の数々の伝説に
なぞらえてあって➡
Each chapter reads like one of
your numerous legendary exploits.
何か 自伝小説っぽくて…。
It's almost like an autobiography.
この本の主人公… 最後まで➡
The main character of this book...
あきらめなかったところが
かっこよかった。
I thought his determination to
never give up was really cool...
先生らしいですね この主人公。
He's a lot like you, Sensei.
そ… そうかのぉ？
Y-You think so...?
で… オレ 思ったんです。
ん？
So I was thinking.
今度 生まれてくる子供も➡
Huh?
I really hope my unborn child
こんな主人公みたいな忍に
なってくれたらいいな って。
can become a ninja just
like this main character!
だから この小説の主人公の名前
いただいてもいいですか？
Which is why I'd like your permission
to name my son after him.
お… おい！
そんなんで いいのか？
H-Hey! Are you sure?
ラーメン 食いながら
適当に決めた名前だぞ。
It's just a random name that
I thought up while eating ramen.
(クシナ)ナルト…。
Naruto...
ステキな名前です。
It's a wonderful name.
クシナ…。
Kushina...
アハハハ… ったく… ってことは
わしが名づけ親かのぉ？
Cripes...
So that makes me his godfather?
わしなんかで 本当にいいのか？
Are you really sure about this?
先生だからこそです。
You are my sensei!
本当の忍の才能を持つ
立派な忍者で➡
And you are a great shinobi who possesses
the true talent of a ninja!
(あなたほどの忍は
いませんからね))
There's no other like you.
《そうだ… そうだった。
わしは あの子に…》
Yes...
That's right...
I gave that child...
((ナルト : オレってば 火影になる!!
I'm gonna become the Hokage!
そんでもって どの火影をも超える
火影になるんだ！
A Hokage that surpasses
all previous Hokage!
(まっすぐ 自分の言葉は曲げねえ。
それが オレの忍道だ！))
I never go back on my word...
That's my ninja way!
《ナルト… 思えば お前は
あの小説の主人公どおりだ。
Naruto...
Now that I think about it, Naruto,
you are just like that
novel's main character.
ミナトとクシナの想い… 願いを
ちゃんと受け取っていた。
You've inherited Minato and
Kushina's wishes, their hopes...
それなのに わしは…》
And yet... I...
((先生だからこそです。
You are my sensei!
本当の忍の才能を持つ
立派な忍者で➡
And you are a great shinobi who
possesses the true talent of a ninja!
(あなたほどの忍は
いませんからね))
There's no other like you.
((忍者とは
忍び堪える者のことなんだよ。
A ninja is one who endures,
one who stands brave.
ひとつ テメエに教えといてやる。
Let me teach you one thing...
忍の才能で いちばん大切なのは
持っている術の数なんかじゃねえ。
The most important attribute
of a ninja
is not the number of jutsu he masters.
(大切なのは
あきらめねえ ド根性だ！))
The most important thing is...
the guts to never give up!
《まっすぐ
自分の言葉は曲げない。
Never go back on your word
and never give up...
そして どんなときも
あきらめない。
それが お前の忍道なら…
ナルトよ！ わしは そのお前の師だ。
Naruto, if that is your ninja way...
Then as your mentor...
弱音を吐くわけにはいかんのぉ。
I have no business whining.
なぜなら 弟子の忍道は
師匠ゆずりと相場は決まっとる。
For everyone knows that a student
inherits his ninja way from his teacher!
なぁ そうだろ？ ナルトよ。 のぉ!!》
Isn't that so, Naruto?!
《気力で吹き返したんか!?》
He fought his way back by sheer will?!
自来也ちゃん！
Jiraiya-chan!
心の臓は止まっていたはずだが…。
I was sure his heart had stopped.
よし！
Got it!
くっ…。
《あきらめねえ…。
Never give up...
それこそが わしの取るべき
本当の選択だった！》
That was the true choice
I was supposed to make!
さすがに しぶといな。
片づける。
Quite obstinate, isn't he?
Let's finish him off.
よし！ 確かに受け取ったけんの!!
All right! Message received!
ダイイングメッセージ… 暗号化したか。
A dying message...
He wrote it in code, eh?
《ナルト… 予言の子は
間違いなくお前だ。
Naruto... You are the child of prophecy,
I'm sure of it now.
あとは… すべて託すぞ…》
I entrust you with the rest!
カエルには逃げられたか…。
The frog... got away.
《自来也豪傑物語…。
"The Tale of Jiraiya the Gallant"...
これで ちったぁ
マシになったかのぉ…。
Now it'll end a bit better I hope.
最終章… 井の中の蛙
大海で散る… の巻か。
The final chapter will be...
"The Frog in the Well Drifts
Into the Great Ocean."
フフフ… ほどほどに
あっぱれ あっぱれ…。
Not bad... Not bad at all...
さて… そろそろ
ペンを置くとしよう。
Now... It's about time
I put down my pen...
おお… そうだ！
続編のタイトルは 何がいいかのぉ。
Ah, that's right!
What should I name the sequel?
そうだのぉ…。
Let's see...
『うずまきナルト物語』
うむ… それが いい…》
"The Tale of Naruto Uzumaki."
Yes... That has a nice ring to it...
you are next to me
omae ga tonari ni iru
you are laughing
omae ga waratte iru
you seem so happy
omae ga ureshisou de
so I laughed too
ore mo waratta
you were so innocent and naive
omae wa mujaki datta
you were so kindhearted
omae wa yasashi katta
you sometimes cried
omae wa tokidoki naki
so I was troubled
ore wa komatta
who did I ask strength from at that time
dare yori tsuyosa wo motometa ano koro
since that was my one and only weakness
ore no tatta hitotsu no yowasa ga
that was you
omae datta
and it was you
omae datta n da
I want to see you
aitai
overnights
yoru wo koete
over time
toki wo koete
I want to see you now
ima aitai
《ウルティア : 許せない… 許せない…》
Next Episode
Uchiha Itachi...
You haven't changed, have you?
But I'm no longer the same as before.
私は 煉獄の七眷属が長
ウルティア！
You don't know anything about me...
Of the hatred I carry towards you...
(グレイ)こいよ 不良娘！
And how it helped me
become stronger...
母親に代わって
説教してやらぁ！
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Banquet Invitation"
Don't miss it!
Banquet Invitation